A Team Nanban (594mgnav) Release
"Supreme Court"
Kazuya Soga, get out here!
（看守）ソガ･カズヤ 出ろっ！
- Griffin Unit, ten minutes to air-strike.
- Eagle clear.
（春日(かすが)）
グリフォン隊 空爆開始まで10分
（スナイパー１）
イーグルクリア
（スナイパー２）
フォックス ネガティブ
- Griffin Unit,
- Fox negative.
（春日）グリフォン隊
空爆開始まで10分
- ten minutes to air-strike. Griffin Unit,
- Griffin here. Roger that.
（ソガ）
こちらグリフォン 了解！
- ten minutes to air-strike.
- It's clear!
（スナイパー２）
ログ イッツ クリア
（兵士）手榴弾！
（ソガ）待て 人質がいる！
- Tossing hand grenade.
- Wait! They've got hostages.
（ソガ）援護を！
Request support!
（テロリスト１）うわっ
（テロリスト２）うわっ
（テロリスト３）うわっ…
We hereby issue the final verdict
on defendant Kazuya Soga.
（裁判官）ただいまより 被告人
ソガ･カズヤの確定判決を申し渡す
（裁判官）被告人は
カルディスタン戦においての―
It is evident that the defendant
committed crimes against humanity
非人道的行為は明白である
during the fighting in Qhardistan.
Therefore, this war crimes court
hereby sentences...
よって主文 戦犯法廷は…
ハァ… ハァ…
（ソガ）ハァ… ハァ…
.::FLiCKSiCK 1080p::.
Strange... Why am I awake when
everyone else is sleep-learning?
はて みんな 睡眠学習中なのに
なぜ僕だけが？
（ヴィヴィー）君の賢いおつむ
貸してちょうだい
Lend me that clever little brain of yours.
Who are you?
（ロジコマ）君は誰…？
僕の並列化を更新している君は…
Who is that updating my synchronization?
僕かつ 君…
You and me...?
Huh?
We're doing this to clear our
names and Colonel Soga's!
（バトー）俺たちとソガ大佐の
無実を証明するためだ！
モジュールを運び出せ
Get the module into the vehicle!
It's a secret.
（ヴィヴィー）内緒よ
（ロジコマ）あっ！
（素子(もとこ)）ん？
Last night, all of Public Security's systems
went down for just 1.8 seconds.
（荒巻(あらまき)）昨夜 1,8秒間だけ
公安の全システムがダウンした
（素子）ミス？ エラー？
ハッキング？
Mistake? Error? Hacking?
（鑑識官）調査中です
We're investigating.
（鑑識官）ただ このロジコマだけ
何かと並列化した可能性がある
But there's a possibility that this one
Logicoma synched with something.
（素子）何か…？
"Something"?
I want you to find out what--and how
it's related to the system going down.
（荒巻）それを調べてほしい
システムダウンに関する
因果関係もな
（素子）旧式のニューロチップＡＩ
What freak would bother accessing
an Al with an outdated neurochip,
しかも しゃべって歩くだけの
コンベイヤーに―
not to mention a conveyer
that can only walk and talk?
わざわざアクセスする物好きいる？
何であれ このロジコマは独立封鎖
他の機体は停止
In any case, we're leaving the
others off and isolating this one.
I'd like you to investigate it, too.
調査も同様に頼む
内部の犯行を警戒ってわけね
In other words, you're worried
it was an inside job.
いいわ 民間の施設を使う
All right, I'll use a civilian facility.
できれば 独立した部隊に
頼みたかったがな
I would have liked to go to an
independent squad with this...
いまだに人材の吟味中か？
Still looking for the perfect personnel?
It is my team. I intend to take care.
自分の部隊よ
念入りにやるわ
気楽なコンサルト暮らしは
クセになるぞ
People can get addicted to
the carefree consultant life.
それとも 部隊の優先度を
なるべく上げてから設立したいか？
Or are you waiting to form it until
it's a higher priority for the brass?
（荒巻）部隊を
長期存続させたいのなら―
If you want the squad to last,
don't get overly ambitious.
余計な色気を出さんことだ
Your parallel commands are randomized?
（素子）並列コマンドを
ランダム化してるわけ？
意味あるの？
Is there a point to that?
（ロジコマ）僕たちの学習には
最適なんです
It's best for our learning.
こっちと規格が合わないわ
It's outside my system standards.
あなたが受信したデータを
言葉で説明できる？
Can you explain the data you received verbally?
Um, I feel like it was
something really important...
何か とっても大事な
ことだったような…
I see it was completely integrated.
（素子）完全に溶け込まれたわね
誰がやったか知らないけど
いい腕してるわ
Whoever did this, they're good.
（ロジコマ）
何だか ドキドキします
I feel sort of fluttery.
There's no record of the infiltrator.
侵入者の記録なんてないわ
完全に溶け込まれたうえに
疑似記憶まで噛(か)まされちゃって…
Not only were you fully integrated,
you got yourself bitten by false memories too.
I got bitten?!
（ロジコマ）噛まされた
わ～お！
Precious experience points!
貴重な経験値！
Bingo.
ビンゴ！
（ロジコマ）
わぁ～ それが僕の中に！？
Wow, that was inside me?! I'm amazing!
すごい 僕！
Yeah, yeah. They really are good.
ホント いい腕してるわ
I'm saying that for a soldier,
（イシカワ）同国人を撃つのは―
軍人として最低の堕落だって
言ってんだよ！
killing your own countrymen
is as low as you can sink!
What's this?
なぁに？
（ボーマ）大佐と俺たちの無実を
立証するための行動だ
We're doing it to prove
our innocence, and the colonel's!
（バトー）
早くモジュールを運…
Just get the module--
A traffic control error?
交通管制のエラー？
What, what, what?!
（ロジコマ）何？ 何？ 何～？
（素子）あっ ロジコマ！
Logicoma!
もうっ！
Sheesh!
（ロジコマ）うわあ～お～！
（素子）いきなり 何なの！？
Why is everyone suddenly crazy?!
Motoko Kusanagi...
草薙(くさなぎ)素子…
（イシカワ）草薙って501の三佐か
Kusanagi? The major with the 501?
（バトー）今は独立したはずだ
Pretty sure she's independent now.
Call in all deployed
personnel as reinforcements.
展開中の部隊を増援に回せ
An assault?
襲撃？
It's raining military-grade bullets.
（素子）軍用火器の雨あられ―
交通管制のエラーに乗じてきたわ
They took advantage of a traffic control error.
Assuming you aren't
setting me up, send backup.
あなたが私をハメようと
してるんじゃなければ―
応援よこして
The attackers are battle cyborgs.
One of them is Batou, the sleepless eye.
襲撃者は戦闘サイボーグ
中に“眠らない眼の男”
バトーがいた
What?!
（荒巻）何だと！？
（素子）ロジコマのＡＩに
噛まされたデータに―
I found a strange code in the data
planted in the Logicoma's AI.
妙なコードが含まれていたわ
標的は それか！
So that's their objective.
ロジコマを自衛モードに
15分で増援を回す
Put the Logicoma in self-defense mode.
I'll have backup there in fifteen minutes.
Fifteen?!
（素子）15分！？
The traffic network is being taken over.
交通網へのドミネーションが
実行されているのだ
Report.
状況は？
Domination expanding throughout the city.
（オペレーター１）
ドミネーション 都市全域に拡大中
（荒巻）何をしている
食い止めろ！
Well, hurry up and stop it!
We don't have enough processing speed.
（オペレーター２）
処理速度 間に合いません
（ドライバー）あっ あ あれ？
Huh?
Penetration increasing.
Defensive advance ineffective.
（オペレーター３）侵攻増大
防衛アドバンス無効
Locking down the airport now.
（管制官１）
これより空港を閉鎖する
（管制官２）ＮＡＮ255便
ゴーアラウンド
- We have a malfunction in the new control system, cause unknown.
- Divert all flights to surrounding airports.
着陸事故により滑走路を…
- Flight A885, the airport is
- Send those with extra fuel furthest away.
- Shut down due to a crash.
- Tell Tokyo Control to return all landing planes to...
（オペレーター１）航空管制―
Both air-traffic control and the new
street traffic system are affected.
新交通システムにも
影響が出ています
（オペレーター２）
交通管制システムの
すでに８割が―
80% of the street system has been
taken over by an outside operator.
外部からの操作で
乗っ取られています
（荒巻）バカな
This is crazy--what enormous
system is our hacker using?!
相手は どこの巨大システムを
使用しているというのだ！？
Major, fifteen minutes will be a problem.
少佐 15分は難しくなった
You're joking!
（素子）冗談！
This isn't an error. It's a crime.
これはエラーではない…
犯罪だ！
Large-scale domination?!
Who has a system like that?!
（素子）大規模ドミネーション！
どこに そんなシステムが！？
Give me weapons!
武器を出して
Why are you empty ?!
なんで 空なのよ！
I was being inspected.
（ロジコマ）検査中でしたから
Guess I'll set up an ambush.
（素子）どこかで
こちらから仕掛けるか
You hear that, Borma?
Get it done in ten minutes.
（バトー）聞こえたな ボーマ
10分でカタをつけろ
解除コードを公安に使わせるな…
Don't let Public Security
use the de-parallelizing code.
Borma!
ボーマ！
（ボーマ）うっ くそったれ！
You bitch!
く… あんなゲテモノをどこで…
Where'd they get that crap?
The range of domination is
still expanding, you know.
（ヴィヴィー）ドミネーションの
規模は今なお 拡大中よ
The only solution is to get the module.
（ヴィヴィー）
解決にはモジュールを
押さえる以外に手はないわ
Who are you? You've been spying
on me since I left Public Security.
（素子）誰？ 公安ビルを
出る時から覗(のぞ)いていたな？
To ask for your help. I want you to
trust me and hand over the conveyer.
（ヴィヴィー）協力を求めるためよ
私を信用してコンベイヤーを
引き渡してほしいの
I recognize your voice from yesterday...!
（素子）その声… 昨日の！
Yes. I'm the one who infiltrated him.
（ヴィヴィー）
そう 彼に侵入したのは 私
And Public Security's system going down?
（素子）公安のシステムダウンも？
（ヴィヴィー）それは私じゃないわ
That wasn't me.
That was the first move of the group
今 特殊な軍事用モジュールを
用い―
using a special military module to carry
out' a large-scale cyber operation.
大規模な電子的作戦を
行っている者たちの布石
"Operation"?
（素子）作戦だと！
Here I go!
（ロジコマ）よいしょ！
はっ ロジコマ！
Logicoma!
The enemy stole the module's
de-parallelizing code from me.
（ヴィヴィー）敵は私から―
モジュールの
並列解除コードを奪った
All I could do was replicate the code
私に可能だったのは
並列解除コードの複製と―
and copy it to an isolation-capable
AI they couldn't interfere with.
敵が手出しできない
独立閉鎖可能なＡＩに―
それを移すことだけ
You, in other words.
つまり そこの君にね
（ロジコマ）やっぱり 僕は
すごい秘密を持ってたんだ！
I knew it! I do carry an incredible secret!
（ヴィヴィー）フッ そうね
（ロジコマ）おっとと
- Indeed.
- Oh, dear.
Logicoma, full speed. Get us to the exit!
とばせ！ ロジコマ！ 出口だっ！
（ロジコマ）アイ アイサー！
Ave ave, sir!
前！
- Face front!
- Aaand stop!
（ロジコマ）ストーップ
（素子）おいっ！
- Hey!
- Huh?
（ロジコマ）あれ？
Huh?
あれ？
Huh...?
あれ～？
Shield!
（素子）シールド！
（ロジコマ）あれ？ 壊れてない！
Huh?! I'm not broken.
Where'd this "military module" come from?
その軍事モジュールって
やつの出どころは？
It's a Mass Field-Hacking Unit jointly
developed with seven leading companies
（ヴィヴィー）旧シリコンバレーの
大手７社が共同開発した―
in the old Silicon Valley.
マスフィールドユニットよ
Military joint production?
Are you an American agent?
軍事共産…
お前 米軍の情報部か？
I'm Special Forces.
（ヴィヴィー）特殊作戦部隊所属
コードネーム ヴィヴィー
My code name is "VV". I'm supporting
you in hope of your cooperation.
協力を期待して支援する
Great, now we've got two enemies.
（イシカワ）
敵が２人に増えやがった
So that agent came to take back the module.
例のエージェントがモジュールを
取り返しに来たか
だが 惑わされるな
But don't let her throw you.
公安の機体さえ破壊すれば
チェックメイトだ
All we have to do is destroy the Public
Security machine, and it's checkmate.
How's the domination coming?
ドミネの進行状況は？
We're close to target values.
（イシカワ）目標値まで あと少し
（バトー）
これ以上 好き勝手させねえ
We won't let 'em get away with anything else.
Get me a line and connect to the colonel.
ライン構築 大佐につなげ
This war crimes court hereby sentences...
（裁判官）主文―
戦犯法廷は被告ソガ･カズヤを…
Colonel Soga, how dare you?!
（春日）ソガ大佐！ 貴様！
Who the hell are you?!
（警備員）何だね 君は？
The Administrative Vice-Minister of Defense.
I want to talk to that man!
（春日）国防省事務次官だ
その男と話がある
Vice-Minister Kasuga.
I'm flattered by your concern.
（ソガ）春日国防次官どの
気にかけてくださっていたとは
But I create my own circumstances.
だが 自分の状況は自分で作り出す
（春日）何だと！
Excuse me?
Those who obstruct my Net
will disappear from this city.
私のネットを遮る者は
この都市から消え去る
（ソガ）私の望みは ただ１つ
I only desire one thing...
我々の真実を明らかにすることだ
To make our truths known!
Aramaki, I assume you've heard of Soga?
（役人）荒巻
ソガは知っているな？
Kazuya Soga, the war criminal in
the Qhardistan massacre, correct?
（荒巻）ソガ･カズヤ―
カルディスタン虐殺事件の
戦犯でしたな
He's the man behind this traffic chaos.
現在の交通網の混乱…
やつが首謀者だ
He's still connected to the Net even
after we tossed him in an isolation cell.
隔離室へブチ込んでも
ネットに つながり続けている
Can't the great Section 9 stop him?!
君たちでも 止められんのか！
He's on an independent line
via military satellite.
（荒巻）
軍事衛星による独立ラインです
We'd have to open a hole
in our tactical defenses:
戦術的空白を覚悟で
ラインごと消すか―
either kill the line with him,
or shoot down the satellite.
衛星を落とすか
Out of the question!
論外だ
Then our hands are tied for the moment.
では 現時点での対抗は不可能
Even with all Home Affairs and civilian Als
working at full capacity, we wouldn't have
内務省および 民間ＡＩを
フル稼働させても―
彼のコマンドを絶ち―
the processing power to break his command
and take back the traffic control systems.
交通管制システムを
掌握し返すまでの―
処理能力は得られません
They made him a scapegoat
when he refused to testify in court.
（春日）
彼は法廷での証言を拒み―
いけにえゲームの標的にされた
I did what I could to commute his sentence...
私としては最大限―
彼の罪が軽減されるよう
働きかけたが…
But I never thought he'd mobilize his unit!
まさか 部隊を動かすとは
His motive is clear, anyway.
動機は明白ですな
To an honest soldier, a postwar
military purge is a state betrayal.
まっとうな軍人にとって―
戦後の粛正人事は国家の裏切りだ
Well, have a seat.
まあ かけたまえ…
Where did his unit get those weapons?
（荒巻）部隊の所持している
武器の出どころは？
The lower-ranking NCOs are on strike right now,
（春日）
下級下士官はストライキ中でね
so it wouldn't surprise anyone
if a whole arsenal disappeared.
倉庫の中身が
ごっそり消えても驚かんよ
One last thing, then: What's he after?
では もう１つ 彼の目的は？
He's demanding access to a military database...
（春日）大佐の要求は
軍事データベース
...called "Pandora".
“パンドラ”へのアクセスだ
政府管理機密に…
State secrets?
軍が行った作戦の詳細を
戦犯法廷に提出する気ですか？
Does he mean to bring the details of an
Army operation before the war crimes court?
That's not all.
（春日）それだけではない
（荒巻･役人）ん？
He wants to air the Army's and Public
Security's dirty laundry to the world
都市2,000万台の車と
人命を盾に―
過去の公安や軍の機密を
全世界に公開するつもりだ
in exchange for this city's 20 million
cars and the people in them.
He wants Japan itself to be judged,
just like he was judged?
自分が裁かれるように―
この国そのものを
世界に裁かせると？
Other countries would use war crimes
as a pretext for all sorts of demands...
（春日）そうなれば 諸外国は
戦中犯罪を大義名分に―
占領下にも等しい
あらゆる要求を突きつけてくる
We might as well be under occupation again.
我が国は戦後
最も後れを取った国として―
As the war's greatest losers, our country
would be the world's puppet state.
世界に隷属することになるのだ
It doesn't even bear discussing!
We'll never give in to that demand!
（役人）判断するまでもない
そんな要求は絶対に のめん！
Are you speaking on behalf of Home Affairs?
（春日）それは
内務省の代表見解ですかな？
（役人）そ そうではない だが…
N-No! But...
Colonel Kazuya Soga?
（素子）ソガ･カズヤ大佐？
He commanded an op in Qhardistan
that won him high praise.
（荒巻）カルディスタンで
軍事作戦を指揮して―
高い評価を得た人物だ
その際に虐殺行為を
行ったとされ―
Then he was accused of conducting
a massacre during the op
and convicted as a war criminal.
He's currently in custody.
戦犯として判決がくだり
身柄は今 拘束中だ
A hero during the war, and a criminal afterward.
（ヴィヴィー）戦争では英雄
戦後は犯罪者
And Soga's sympathizers are using
the module to seek his release?
そのシンパがモジュールを武器に
ソガ大佐の釈放でも求めていると？
Major--
少佐！？
情報提供者よ！
She's an informant. I brought
her in on a provisional basis.
仮登録で私が入れたの
What exactly is this "module"?
（荒巻）
そのモジュールとやらは何だ？
（素子）国家規模の
巨大システム並みの処理能力を―
It creates processing power on
the level of a giant nationwide system.
作り出す軍事モジュール
ソガのシンパは それを使って―
They must have used it to parallelize
something low-capacity in huge quantities.
低容量の何かを
大量に並列化したのよ
（荒巻）貴官の意見は？
Your opinion?
草薙少佐と同意見
I agree with Major Kusanagi.
では 貴官の目的は
モジュールの奪還か？
And is your objective to retrieve the module?
もしくは破壊…
Or destroy it.
The most effective method is to use
the code I evacuated into your Al
最も効果的な手段は―
私が そちらのＡＩに
緊急避難させた―
モジュールの並列解除コードを―
from somewhere free of enemy interference.
敵の干渉のない状況下で
使用することです
Why was it stolen in the first place?
（荒巻）
そもそも なぜ盗難された？
The module was a model brought here for
top-secret standards sharing with Japan.
（ヴィヴィー）
盗まれたモジュールは―
日本側と極秘に規格共有するために
持ち込まれたモデルタイプです
I take it your colleagues are making a
top-secret investigation of the theft?
（荒巻）ということは
盗難の経緯は―
そちらの同僚が
極秘裏に調査中かね？
I'll leave that to your imagination.
ご想像にお任せします
（荒巻）敵の中継点を
特定した方法もかね？
Along with how you pinpointed
the enemy's smuggling point?
Both issues are the purview of the
Administrative Vice-Minister of Defense,
どちらも
国防省事務次官の管轄だが―
but he didn't mention them
when I spoke to him just now.
先ほど話した時
次官殿は何も言わなかった
Evidently something's being hushed up.
何やら 伏せていることが
あるらしいな
Another reason I want you
（素子）その件も含め―
内務省に私の部隊を最優先ラインで
扱うように言ってちょうだい
to tell the Ministry of Home Affairs
to give my squad top priority.
Since when do you have a squad?!
部隊だと？
そんなものが どこに！
これから作るのよ
I'm about to form one. Based on skill,
with no ranks, and given top priority.
階級無しの実力主義最優先ラインを
Bad plan! Special forces
teams aren't mercenaries!
やめんか！
特務部隊は傭兵(ようへい)ではない
事件を自分個人の
チャンスにするなど―
If you take advantage of
a disaster for your own gain,
the defense world will treat you like a vulture!
治安関係者から
ハゲタカ扱いされるぞ
（素子）
代償を欲しがる部隊にも―
I'm not interested in teams out for money
or ministry bigwigs gunning
for postwar concessions.
戦後の利権に必死の省庁幹部にも
関心ないわ
聞くけど 内務省幹部の現状は？
Tell me this: How are the
Home Affairs higher-ups?
国防省ともども
エリートパニックを起こしとる
Having themselves an "elite panic"
with the Ministry of Defense.
They're afraid the public
will panic if word gets out,
情報が流れれば 国民が
パニックになるのではと恐れ―
so other than a few of my units,
they won't order anyone to act.
一部 公安部隊にしか
対処を命じようとせん
We're the only ones who can act right now.
（素子）今 動けるのは私たちだけ
A team formed on a fixed standard that
will be necessary everywhere in every age.
どんな時代 どんな状況であっても
必要とされる―
完成された規格による部隊！
So it's finally taking off.
ようやく芽吹いたか
（サイトー）へっ
また 生き残っちまったぜ
Whoops, survived again.
（素子）仮想現実で
ロシアン･ルーレット？
Playing Russian roulette in a virtual reality?
Do you reproduce the sensation of the
bullet penetrating your cranium, too?
頭蓋骨を貫通される
感覚まで再現してるのか？
You've got a sickness.
病気だな お前
Kusanagi from the 501!
When did you sneak in here?!
三佐！？ いつの間に
入ってきやがった！？
I'm independent. The op in Qhardistan,
the American Army module, and Soga...
少佐だ
カルディスタンでの軍事作戦
米軍製モジュール ソガ大佐
心当たりを話すか
リアルで弾を食らうか 選べ
Tell me what you know, or take
a real-life bullet. Your choice.
（サイトー）待て なんで俺に…
Hold on! Why come to me?
You served under Soga in Qhardistan.
（素子）カルディスタンで
大佐の下にいたな
お前の個人ラインに イシカワが
呼びかけた痕跡があったぞ
There's a record of lshikawa
calling you on your private line.
Hey, I turned down the job with the 78th!
The pay wasn't good enough.
（サイトー）
78部隊のことなら俺は断った
ギャラが見合わなかったからだ
（素子）
海兵隊エース･スナイパーが―
The Marines' ace sniper turned into
a compulsive gambler after the war?
戦後はギャンブル狂い？
休職中の部隊予算が―
Is that why your unit's leave-time
budget's been cooked to high hell?
相当 粉飾されているのも
そのせい？
How did you know--
なんで それを… うおっ
If your postwar days are about
turning your life into cash,
自分の命を金に換えるのが
お前の戦後なら―
I'll play your game.
代償に付き合ってやる
Join my spec ops team in the next five seconds,
私の特務部隊への転属を
５秒以内に承認するか―
or the money you embezzled gets
transferred to Maritime Command.
使い込んだ額が
海軍司令部に転送されるかだ
くそったれ
Bitch.
I'll pay you a salary.
給料は弾むわよ
The radio's still up, right? Divert everyone
before we lose the whole system.
（主任管制官）システムが
ダウンし切る前にダイバードさせろ
So you're the MP?
あんたが陸軍警察？
What'd she threaten you with to bring you in?
おたくは何で脅されて
スカウトされたんだ？
Oh, I volunteered.
（パズ）いや 志願した
少佐が部隊を設立するのを
待ってたんだ
I've been waiting for the
Major to start up her team.
物好きがいるぜ
You're a messed-up guy.
How can you control this
with the domination going on?
（素子）ドミネーションの最中に
なぜ制御できる？
This antique has some special specifications.
年代物の特殊仕様よ フフッ
It's in a whole different class from
your friend's old clunker there!
あなたのお友達の旧型とは
一味も二味も違うの！
Since we can't cut Soga's Net,
we'll have to physically seize the module.
ソガ大佐のネットを
断てない以上―
モジュールを直接
押さえるしかない
敵の拠点である可能性が
最も高い施設がここよ
This facility is the most likely
candidate for our enemy's base.
（素子）餌の在りかを与えるだけで
自分の手は汚したくないわけね
I see; you'll only give us our target's location.
You don't want to get your own hands dirty.
私 潔癖症なの
I'm a neat freak.
An old communications equipment company, eh?
元通信設備会社の施設か
Not much for a sniper to do if
they're holed up in a server room.
サーバー室に閉じこもられちゃ
狙撃手の出番はないな
Don't worry, I'll smoke out
plenty of targets for you.
心配ない
あぶり出して たっぷり
的を用意してやるよ
Bingo? Seriously?
（サイトー）ビンゴかよ
Just one squad, and they get their
own ground support chopper...
小隊１個規模
対地支援用ヘリまである…
Good grief.
やれやれだ…
（素子）行くぞ ロジコマ！
We're going, Logicoma.
Huh? But I'm not done with the sensors...
（ロジコマ）えっ！？
まだ 対人センサーを！
ええっ 何ですとっ！
What?! Really?!
- Safe...
- You're slow!
（ロジコマ）セーフ
（素子）タイミング遅いぞ！
（ロジコマ）えっ？
（見張り１）うっ！
（見張り２）うっ
Paz, status?
（素子）パズ どうだ？
Not sure whether it went well or not, but I'm in.
（パズ）うまくいったかどうかは
分からんが潜り込んだ
So are we. Report if you find the module.
（素子）こちらもだ
モジュールを発見したら知らせろ！
Let's do this.
やるぞ
No use!
（ソガ）無駄だ！
（素子）はっ！？
防壁迷路！ あっ
A barrier maze?
この処理速度…
This processing speed...
You people can't stop my Net.
（ソガ）お前たちには
私のネットは止められない！
In about an hour, Pandora's lid will open.
あと１時間ほどで
パンドラのフタが開く
It's impossible to stop me before then.
それまでに私を止めることは
不可能だ
そうまでして国に報復したいか！
You want revenge against
the country that badly?
I'm uncovering the truth.
真実の解明だ！
The op to move the refugees in Qhardistan
（ソガ）カルディスタンでの
難民移送作戦
was the 78th Composite Unit's final mission.
混成78部隊 最後の任務だった
お前が指揮した殲滅(せんめつ)作戦か？
Which was an extermination op you led?
（ソガ）違う！
No!
これは
This is...
They were unarmed refugees.
（ソガ）武器を持たない
難民たちだった
Afterward, a conglomerate occupied their land.
その後 複合企業が
彼らの土地を占有した
国益のための虐殺を命じた者がいる
Someone ordered their slaughter
to benefit the national interest.
Give me water!
水をくれ！
うっ うっ ハァ
ハァ フッ
This is the first step.
（ソガ）これは手始めだ
I'll put all the nations who led the
world into war in that same position.
世界を戦争に導いた
全ての国家に―
同じ状況になってもらう
Soga! You've been inf--
ソガ！ お前は か…
Soga?
ソガ！
This is... a gap in the maze, maybe?
ここは…
（素子）メイズの隙間か何か？
How did she leave the
barrier maze? No--she didn't.
なぜ 防壁迷路から…
いや 違う
Soga can't see me?
ソガからは見えない？
やはり うまく隙間に落ちた
I did manage to land in a gap.
An accident-prevention AI?!
事故防止用ＡＩ
He's parallelized all the Als
in Japan's traffic network!
国内全ての
交通網ＡＩを並列化！
（ソガ）ふんっ
危なかったわね！
That was close.
私の張った防壁も長くは保てない！
My barrier won't last long. Let's hurry.
急ぎましょ！
It's been three minutes since we
lost contact with Major Kusanagi.
（オペレーター）
草薙少佐との連絡が途絶え―
３分が経過しています
国防省より連絡
Call from the Ministry of Defense.
４分前より“パンドラ”の防壁に
論理攻撃が…
A DoS attack on the Pandora
barrier began four minutes ago.
We can't keep up with it.
遮蔽(しゃへい)処理が追いつきません
（荒巻）うむ…
Sounds like it was a mistake to
give Public Security free rein!
君たちを泳がせておいたのは
間違いだったようだ
You invited this by carelessly stirring Soga up!
ソガを不用意に刺激したことで
この事態が招かれた
Major! Are you all right?
What's the situation?
少佐！ 無事か！？
状況は？
Soga took over the traffic control
system through the module.
（素子）大佐はモジュールを介して
交通管制システムを制圧した
But the threat to kill if we
didn't release Pandora was fake.
でも 人命を盾にパンドラの
解放を迫ったのはフェイク
He intends to use the vast
system power he's gained
稼いだ ばく大な
システムパワーで―
パンドラを こじ開けるつもりよ
to break Pandora wide open.
I see...
そうか！
In that case, there are steps we can take.
そういうことなら
こちらにも打つ手はある
You keep working to recover the module.
お前は引き続き―
モジュールの奪還を頼む
Nice timing!
（素子）いいタイミングだ！
The deal with the government should be a bluff.
（バトー）政府との取り引きは
ブラフのはずだ
Colonel Soga went too far.
（兵士１）ソガ大佐は やり過ぎた
This started as a plan for the
Vice-Minister to sell Pandora!
もとは次官がパンドラを
売るための作戦だぞ
We can't survive turning
the whole world against us!
世界を敵に回して
生き残れるものか
If you've got cold feet, run.
Nobody'll stop you.
ビビったんなら逃げな
誰も止めねえよ
取り引きでも何でも勝手にしろ
Negotiate a deal or whatever.
I sure will!
（兵士１）そうするさっ！
（兵士２）ああっ うっ
金目当てなら おとなしく逃げろ
If you're in this for money, run without a fight.
（兵士２）うっ…
（兵士３）ああ あっ… ひぃー
おい！
Hey! Home Affairs just gave us money!
内務省が金を
振り込んじまったぞ！
欲しいやつに くれてやれ！
Give it to someone who cares!
（イシカワ）うーん
（バトー）撤退する
We're withdrawing. I'll buy some time.
時間を稼ぐぞ！
大佐は78部隊の戦犯容疑を
晴らすのも待たなかった
The colonel didn't even wait
to clear the 78th's name.
なぜだと思う？
Why do you figure that is?
Kasuga!
春日次官…
大佐はスケープゴートに
The colonel got scapegoated...!
行くぞ！
Let's go!
I'll meet up with you once I've stalled them.
（イシカワ）
やつらの足止めをして合流する
Do it fast.
（バトー）急げよ！
（素子）パズ！ 聞こえるか！
Paz, do you read me?
（パズ）何とか
More or less.
Do you know an intelligence
man named lshikawa?
（素子）情報部のイシカワを
知ってるか
Sure do.
（パズ）知ってる！
If you find him, use a cable
to get him to the cyber lobby.
（素子）見つけたら有線で
電脳ロビーへ誘え！
（パズ）了解！
Roger!
I'm hanging up before they detect our line.
（素子）ラインを発見される
切るぞ！
（イシカワ）くそっ
Shit. The colonel's got domination,
but they're still roaming free!
大佐がドミネを実行中だってのに
平気で動き回ってやがる
Don't underestimate me. I can locate
even a super-wizard-class hacker
（イシカワ）ナメるな
超ウィザード級
ハッカーだろうが
if they make a call during domination!
ドミネの最中に通信すりゃ
位置くらい分かるんだよ
少佐が あんたに用がある
The Major's got business with you.
Let me connect you, and nobody gets hurt.
おとなしく有線させてくれれば
ケガは させねぇ
やってみろ 若造
Try it, kiddo. I'll play with you.
遊んでやるよ
（イシカワ）ふんっ
Be a good boy, and you won't get hurt.
（イシカワ）おとなしくすりゃあ
ケガはしねぇよ！
あんたがな
You mean you won't.
She was playing me with that call?
Damn gorilla woman!
くそっ 通信は おとりか
あのゴリラ女！
Who are you calling a gorilla?
（素子）誰がゴリラだって？
Major Kusanagi!
（イシカワ）草薙少佐！
Planning to stick me with a virus?
俺にウイルスを仕込む気か
The opposite. I think you're already infected.
逆だ 恐らく感染している
What?
（イシカワ）何！？
It's a makeshift vaccine, so you'll
have to put up with any bugs.
（素子）不具合は我慢しろ
仮設で構築したワクチンだ
（バトー）イシカワとの
連絡が途切れた
I've lost contact with lshikawa.
I'll go.
俺が行く！
I'll take the module and go on ahead.
We rendezvous at the trap!
モジュールを持って先行する
例のトラップの場所で合流だ！
Roger!
（ボーマ）了解！
出せ！
Drive.
くそ！
Shit. You, Saito?!
（バトー）サイトー！ てめえか！
（サイトー）お互いプロだ
We're all pros here. No holding a grudge.
恨みっこなしだぜ
If you're a pro, join the side that pays best.
（バトー）プロなら
報酬のいい方につけ
Home Affairs paid us.
I'll give you a triple share.
内務省が金を払った
３人分を お前にやる
Take it from my account!
俺の口座を経由して受け取れ！
For real?!
（サイトー）マジかよ
（ボーマ）ああっ イシカワ…
lshikawa!
C'mon, let's get back to guarding the module.
早くモジュールの援護に戻るぞ
Don't move.
（イシカワ）動くな
なっ！？ おい イシカワ！
Hey! lshikawa?!
Major! They all left.
Only one car stayed behind.
（ロジコマ）少佐！
１台だけ残して
みんな 出かけちゃいましたよ！
ダメでした！
- It didn't work!
- Damn, they pulled out already?
（素子）チッ！ もう撤退か！
They've got good judgment.
いい判断をする
Paz, you go in VV's car.
I'll go with the Logicoma!
パズはヴィヴィーの車で
私はロジコマと出る！
Saito!
（素子）サイトー
You transferred them money?!
金を振り込んだですと？
Why would you swallow
the enemy's bluff so easily?
敵のブラフに なぜ
そうも たやすく飛びつくのです！
（役人）
ソガ大佐との交渉の結果だ
This is the result of our negotiation with Soga.
We planned to put the money
toward the Economic Amnesty Act,
経済特赦法に
回す予定だった金だが―
but it came from vet pensions that
got slashed in the Army budget cuts.
もとは軍の予算削減で削られた
退役金だよ
Do you honestly think
that's what they're after?!
それが彼らの目的だと
本気で思っているのですか？
Just whose cause are we
supposed to be working for here?
我々は一体 誰の大義名分で
動けばよいのですか！
金は追跡されるし
責任は国防省が取る
The funds will be traced, and the Department
of Defense is taking responsibility.
我が省の組織は動くな いいな？
Our people stay out of this, got it?
（素子）敵の並列回路は確認した？
Did you check up on the
enemy's parallel circuitry?
The on board Als of 20 million
vehicles in this city are in enemy control.
都市内 2,000万台の車両用ＡＩが
敵の制圧下にある
わしの車もだ
Including my car.
システムのパワー負けで
ヘリ１台 まともに飛ばせん
The system is so overpowered we can
hardly manage to move one chopper.
しかし 一時的にだが
この状況を打開する方法はある
But there is a way to turn
the tables, if only temporarily.
Tell me.
（素子）聞かせて
（ロジコマ）突撃～！
Charge!
くっ もう来やがたのか！
Here already?!
Logicoma, the tires!
（素子）ロジコマ タイヤだ！
割り込め！ お前は右だ！
Cut between them. You take right!
車だと！
A car?! How can they move
during our domination?
ドミネの最中に なんで動く
Here we go, Paz.
（ヴィヴィー）パズ 行くわよ！
（ヴィヴィー）運転を奪われた！
He's taken over my car!
"Special specifications", my ass!
（素子）何が特別仕様だ！
聞いてあきれる！
He quit everything to focus some
crazy pressure on me! It's too much!
（ヴィヴィー）
ここだけに集中して―
ものすごいプレッシャーを
かけてきたのよ！
無理よ！
lshikawa!
（素子）イシカワ！
Damn gorilla woman's calling.
ゴリラ女が呼んでやがる…
lshikawa?
イシカワ？
チッ
大佐に脳を焼かれかけるとは…
Shit. Never figured the
colonel'd try to brain-fry me!
I can't believe it--did he really?!
信じられねぇ 本当なのか
We're about to find out what the truth is.
何が真実か これから分かる
I have control!
アイ ハブ コントロール！
んっ
イシカワが あいつらに協力？
Ishikawa's cooperating with 'em?
（素子）サイトー！
Saito!
Sorry, lady, but they sweetened the pot.
（サイトー）悪い
賭けを上乗せされちまった
Good work, Saito!
（バトー）いいぞ サイトー！
We're almost to the trap.
Once we get there...
もうすぐ
予定のトラップの場所だ！
このまま逃げ込めば…
We win!
（サイトー）俺たちの勝ちだ！
You damn gambling-freak mercenary!
（素子）このギャンブル狂いの
傭兵野郎！
Huh? I can't see them anymore.
（ロジコマ）あれ～
分からなくなっちゃいましたね～
This makes no sense.
（素子）おかしい！
Where are they?!
どこだ！？
Five minutes to infiltration of Pandora.
（オペレーター）
パンドラの侵入まで あと５分
（素子）枝葉を付けられた
形跡もないのに―
There's no record that I've been hacked,
so why did they vanish?!
なぜ消えた！
They didn't overwrite your vision.
（ヴィヴィー）
目を盗んだんじゃないわ！
（素子）動けるのか！？
Can you move?!
I lost my right arm, but don't worry--
we're still in the game.
（ヴィヴィー）
右腕を失ったけど大丈夫
まだ いける
So what was their trick?
（素子）で どういうカラクリ？
They used our own skills to
fake us out. Slick of them.
（ヴィヴィー）我々の能力の
裏をかいた うまい手ね
旧式の光学迷彩フォログラフ
It's an old type of optical
camouflage holograph.
I'd have missed it if we weren't going so slowly.
のんびり走ってなきゃ
見逃してた…
I'll send you the location.
ポイントデータを送るわ
Securing the module is top priority.
We're out of time.
（素子）モジュールの確保を
最優先しろ
時間がない！
（バトー）くっ バレたか
They figured it out?
They're damn persistent!
しつこい連中だ！
ええいっ
Fire!
（素子）撃て！
（ロジコマ）あいっ！
Aye!
（ヴィヴィー）
私たちは飛べないから
少し時間がかかるわ
We can't go fast, so it'll take us a bit.
（素子）問題ない
No problem. Logicoma, you stay there.
（素子）ロジコマ そこで待機だ！
（パズ）俺たちが行くまで待て！
Wait until we get to you!
Skilled as always.
さすがだな
But you're not the only one good
at infiltrating vision, 501 Major...
だが 視覚に侵入するのが
得意なのは―
お前だけじゃねぇんだ 草薙三佐
No, just "Major" now.
いや 少佐か…
（パズ）うっ あっ あっ…
（素子）パズ！
Paz!
VV, get the module, fast!
ヴィヴィー
お前は早くモジュールを！
（オペレーター）
パンドラの侵入まで あと10秒
Ten seconds to infiltration of Pandora.
９ ８ ７ ６
9, 8, 7, 6...
（公安局員）１区から38区にかけて
317箇所で検問を敷きました
We set up 317 roadblocks, from Wards 1
through 38. Do we keep going?
まだ 増やしますか？
Mobilize all forces and
put up as many as you can.
総動員だ 可能な限り増やせ！
車両用ＡＩのシステムパワーを
事故回避処理で削る！
We'll tie up all vehicles' on board computers
with accident-avoidance processes.
The fate of our nation is at stake.
国家存亡の危機だ
国交省には悪いが―
I feel bad for the MLIT,
30年ぶりの交通渋滞を
発生させてもらおう
but I'm going to cause the
worst gridlock in thirty years.
Aramaki from Public Security?
（ソガ）公安局の荒巻？
This is his doing?
やつの仕業？
（バトー）ていっ
ええいっ えいっ
Paz!
パズ！
You're too late. Soga's opening
up Pandora as we speak.
（バトー）もう遅いぜ！
今頃 大佐がパンドラを開いてる
（素子）いいや… パワーダウンだ
Nope. His power is down.
走行中だった車両の３割以上を
公安が止めた
Public Security's stopped more than
30% of the vehicles that were in motion.
（素子）お前も ソガ大佐も
感染させられていた
Both you and Colonel Soga
had been deliberately infected.
There is no "truth" about
that refugee transport op.
（素子）難民移送作戦の真実など
存在しない
お前たちが殺し 爆撃を指示した
You killed those people
and ordered an air-strike.
You did it because all the "refugees"
you were trying to safeguard
なぜなら―
お前たちが保護しようとしていた
難民全てが―
were armed guerillas.
武装したゲリラだったからだ
（役人）あとは国防省の責任だ
It's the MOD's responsibility now.
Either do something about him,
or destroy Pandora right now!
彼をどうにかするか
今すぐ パンドラを破壊しろ
Obviously out of the question!
そんなマネが できるものか！
（ソガ）私にパンドラを
開かせるためにか！
Because you want me to open Pandora?
（役人）あっ あっ 何！？
What?
Don't!
（春日）よせ！
（警備兵）貴様ぁ！
You bastard!
Wait! Don't shoot!
（荒巻）待て！ 撃つな！
It was the Administrative Vice-Minister
who gave me the module.
（ソガ）モジュールを渡したのは
国防省次官だ
That agent's objective is the same.
例のエージェントも目的は変わらん
Make sure you don't use
the de-parallelizing code.
並列解除コードは決して使うな
What?
何？
侵入は止められない
I can't stop the infiltration.
This is the only way!
方法は これだけだ
Stop!
やめろ！
（バトー）おおっ
ワクチンの複製を送った
I gave you a copy of the vaccine.
It's imperfect, but you'll be able
to tell which memories are false.
不完全だけど 疑似記憶を
認識できるようになる
It's unlikely we'll be able to
eradicate them, but I'll give you a hand.
記憶を除去できる可能性は低いけど
協力するわ
Not interested.
（バトー）いらねぇよ
It's the only memory that lets me feel
like I'm not just a dog trained to kill!
俺が ただの殺しの犬じゃ
なかったって実感できる―
唯一の記憶なんだ！
You're just a whiny bitch, then.
なら ただの負け犬ね
（荒巻）どうなった 少佐
What happened, Major?!
（素子）
終わったわ 救急隊をよこして
It's over. Send a rescue squad.
（荒巻）終わっただと！？
何を言っとる
W
hat do you mean, "over"?!
パンドラへ侵入された
Pandora's been infiltrated!
The data's being leaked to
a different Net than Soga's!
ソガ大佐と異なるネットに
データが漏えいしているぞ！
モジュールから離れろ！
Step away from the module!
抵抗しないで
Don't resist. I feel an affinity with you.
あなたには共感を覚えている
You, who haven't had a flesh-and-blood
body for as long as you can remember.
自我が芽生えてから一度も―
生身の肉体を持ったことのない
あなたに
You bitch...
貴様…
That attack barrier is meaningless.
（ヴィヴィー）
その攻性防壁は無意味だ
My brain has to be synchronized, like his.
私の脳は彼のように
並列化するしかない
A neurochip? You're...
ニューロチップ…
お前…
I must find out where it came from--
私は探さねばならない
私に感染し―
this thing which infected me
and gave me true self-awareness.
本当の自我を授けてくれた者が
どこから来たのか
Even if I have to access the whole world's
organizations and their secrets...
世界中の機関 世界中の機密に―
アクセスしてでも―
...I Shall.
必ず
人の振りしたＡＩ…
You're an artificial intelligence
pretending to be human...
人工知能とはな…
What for?!
何のために…
（ヴィヴィー）
どうしても知りたくて…
I just have to know.
My Ghost whi... spered... that... to... me...
私のゴーストが―
そう ささやいた…
Ghost...
ゴースト…
（ロジコマ）あれ！？
Huh?
A certain intelligence agency admitted
（荒巻）某情報部が認めた
that one of its Als was infected
with an unknown virus on the Net
彼らのＡＩの１つが―
ネット上で正体不明の
ウイルスに感染し―
and began acting outside of their control.
制御下を離れて独走したそうだ
And it absconded with the module,
で ＡＩが
モジュールを持ち出して―
then manipulated the Vice-Minister.
国防省事務次官を操作した…
He made too many dangerous
deals during the war.
（荒巻）次官は戦争中
危険な取り引きをし過ぎた
He intended to sell the contents
of Pandora and flee the country.
パンドラの中身を売り
亡命する気だったのだ
That's why he manipulated Soga
and sent in a team of his own pawns.
そのために ソガ大佐を操り
自分の手駒の部隊を送り込んだ
But Soga seized control of the situation,
so the Al planned a recovery strategy.
（素子）けれども
大佐に主導権を奪われ―
ＡＩは巻き返しを図った
"A rogue AI did it all"--how very convenient.
全てＡＩの独走だなんて
虫のいい話ね
Even if it's half true, I'm sure they
let things lie to try to profit from her.
話半分としても放置して
利益を得ようとしてたんでしょ
この事件で
利益を得ようとしたのは―
Though it seems they're not the
only ones to try to profit from this.
彼らだけでは なさそうだがな
You're the one who came to me.
最初に依頼したのは そっちよ
With the result that you made
your team a fait accompli
結果 考えられる限りの
優先度で―
お前は部隊を既成事実化した
with the highest possible priority.
Want to re-register as part of Section 9?
何なら ９課の専属として
再登録するか？
They'll cancel this registration
if you can't get enough people together.
スカウトに失敗すれば
人数不足で抹消されるぞ
No thanks.
結構よ
I appreciate your help
with the paperwork, though.
手続きに協力してくれたことには
感謝するわ
（素子）５分で閉まるわ
それまでに決めなさい
It'll close in five minutes.
Decide before then.
そこに座ったまま 流行の
スピード裁判で懲役刑になるか
Sit there and get sentenced in one
of the speed-trials the system loves,
部隊に参加するか
or join my squad.
You say that to everyone you've
been in shooting matches with?
さんざんドンパチした相手に
そう言って回ってんのか お前
釈放可能なのは
疑似記憶の感染者だけ
I can only get people infected
with the memory virus released.
Though those three are the ones I want anyway.
どのみち欲しいのは
その３人だけど
They'll accept that after we just
picked a fight with the government?
国に ケンカを売ったばかりで
認められるのかよ
私と公安９課―
If I, Section 9, and a certain
country's intelligence agency
そして某国の情報部が
疑似記憶について証言すればね
testify about the false memories.
イシカワとボーマは承諾
lshikawa and Borma agreed.
As for Saito, when I paid him a little
visit before he could go to ground,
ちなみに サイトーは―
雲隠れされる前に
挨拶に寄ったら―
he begged me to let him join.
ぜひ参加させてくれって
お願いされたわ
You're some piece of work.
ひでえ女…
So, you're telling me to be
Public Security's errand boy?
で 公安の使いっ走りをしろってか
It's an independent offensive unit
based on skill, with no ranks,
階級無し 実力主義
最優先ライン 独立攻性の部隊だ
and it has top priority.
ただの殺しの犬ではないという
記憶を私が与えてやる
I'll give you memories of being
more than a dog trained to kill.
（バトー）本当に消せるのか
These fake memories--can you really erase 'em?
この偽の記憶を
I can try.
試すことはできるわ
A Team Nanban (594mgnav) Release